[Music]
Every organization in its phases and
lifetime will have different risks so there will be
different risks during the project stage
and the start-up phase there will be a different
risk during the growth stage of the
organization and they will be totally different
stages during the expansion phase of the
organization we need to understand what types
of risks are there for
successful risk management is basically
to transform the uncertainties into
opportunities it's very important you know so more than just
minimize the threat we need to know how to
work on how to take those
opportunities hi
welcome back to oil cafe season two of the
strategy brew my name is kuboo agarwal
and oil brew is the host for this third episode
[Music]
in this episode we will look at the strategies
that have the ability to help businesses grow
in today's fast paced world risk are  Every year the
uncertainties can impair an
organization's capacity to achieve its
objectives but this is very good risk
management techniques come in as a preventative
measure in this episode we are going to talk all about
managing risk and how
organizations can take charge of risk
management today I am joined by Burjan Sarban,
Vice President, Property Risk
Management and Value Added Services welcome
Burjan thank you he is a senior risk
management specialist with 27 years of
industry experience and 12 years at
ICS Lombard he has been to the helm of
risk management practice so Burjan let's
start our first question with a little
bit of history about the term risk
management which was coined by Henri Fayol
in his book titled General and Industrial
Management in 1916
now he describes risk management as a
vital security role among key business
functions like technical commercial
financial security  Accounting and
managerial age we see now that even after a
century later many organizations are still
struggling to completely understand and
implement this notion in your opinion how do
risk management techniques affect an
organization's success or wonderful question actually you know henry fied was a
father of
risk management he in 1916 he understood
what is risk management but that time it was
basically focusing on the security
aspect the risk management is only
focusing on that but it being evolved risk
management is basically all about you know about
safeguarding the organization's
assets it is about you know about safeguarding the
reputation of the organization and also for
the sustainability of the organization so here what we talk about is when we talk about
risk so we see that risk is
into three parts it is three risks which are there
Is basically real risk it is
a perceived risk and inherent risk so
we have to understand which type of risk which are there
and then when we talk about
you know the phases of the organization every
organization in its phase and in its life
time will have different risks so there will be
different risks during the project stage
of the startup phase there will be a different
risk during the you know growth stage of the
organization and there will be totally different
stage during the expansion phase of the
organization so we need to understand what
type of risk are there and how what are
the strategies to you know get it right
and manage those risks and when we have those
risks now when we understand all those
risks we need to have those steps you know to
manage the risk so what are the steps the
steps are basically first we need to
identify it about
assessing  Those risks are
really you know detrimental to the
organization in which way and then it comes about
you know how do you make the strategy to
manage those risks okay and then it comes about
communication inclusion all about the
organization so that it is totally you know
percolated down to the last person and
important here is you know how
comprehensive your risk management
philosophy and your plan is that is also very very
critical and here which we talk about it is
not a one time activity that once I made all this everything is done it is all about
the risk is not static it is
a dynamic risk so it needs to be you know keep on doing this
on a very
periodic level or you can define its
frequency and you can have those stages
where you can do it again and again you know  Do this
exercise so you are totally safe and you know
your organization is sustained I agree risk
assessment should be an ongoing process to stay ahead
of any potential threat for any
sort of organization and this very take on
corporate governance was quite insightful
so moving on burgeon can you also please tell
audience how
organization you know can make sure that their
ongoing risk assessment process is effective
in
identifying
ability also to handle this challenge ya so
kushpu ya no important is that you know one I was talking about
the first question is that already it was only taken care of
me re management took care of taking
safeguarding on the threats but now it has been expanded into many other things ya know this
or so
risk management is basically now focusing on how
it is driving innovation and it is it is you no provide
continuous  Comput
advantage into risk management and also it is
helpful to optimize the performance
of the operation so it is important here I note we
and then we focus on the holistic risk
management so here it is important that we talk
on efficiency as well as safety
together so when we talk both together then it you know
really has a good construct on the
organization and it is good for the long
term resilience important here is to
identify
risk and even benchmarking the risk versus
your own benchmarks and the industry
benchmarks then you go into inclusion of the
entity where you even start from the
leadership and to the ground person on how to
identify the risk so you need to include
the entity into it and then after inclusion once
you have surveyed it and made a dashboard
about it then you go into communication of that so
the entity  Tomorrow then completes when you
start communicating on the
identification
management techniques which are there so that creates
more awareness
okay that's it
and find areas to improve so they are
better prepared for possible
crises also can you cite some examples
of effective risk management tools
currently in use very good question kushpu
so let's talk on you know that again coming back
to my earlier basically talking about that
risk is dynamic and it's holistic
in nature so important here is you know that we can't just keep
risk in the silo it has to be
totally you know like it's like a
bubble you know and in the no drop in the ocean and it has to be
totally perceived with a percolate all in
the organization important here is about
the effective risk management tools as you have ask
so in that  Effective tools is
basically you know about what we do in electrical
GIC also we have lot of tools which we talk about talking starting from
our
property loss prevention plan which is there
so property loss prevention
exercise is an exercise of you know a PDA
cycle PDCA cycle which we have on the
Deming principle we talk about plan do
check act and we entire know when we do this we
totally take care of the 360 ​​degree of the
effort and more important is the
improvement and the implementation phase of
it so we also have means we have curated
solutions for ROI based solutions where we talk about
on the electrical side we see as I said you know we talk
about safety and
we talk about efficiency to where we also give them
energy savings but we also take
care of the electrical
safety of it so we have solutions for
electrical risks  Assessment: We have
comprehensive risk assessment basically for
different types of risk, a smaller risk
and a larger risk. Again, we have also
curated some solutions on the IoT
space, the Internet of Things. So, in the Internet of
Things, we have two patterns to our name and we
have two two patterns mainly for the fire
and the electrical solutions where we take
care of the trigger points of electrical
and also the preparation on the health of the
fire safety systems where they tell us about
and give us automated dashboards which we were talking about
early. They tell us about
two kinds of risks which are
identified. So, when we
identify them, there also we are
acting upon them. We have
our voice system and we talk about
you know early warning science. We go and you know, we send
emails and we talk to our
stakeholders out on a real-time basis.
Before the event and we also go and you know
try to mitigate those risks and see that our
customers who are in danger are not
you know having any problems at that
time so important is you know the learnings
from the Entays that learnings have been
curated by our
experience and the industry experience we have
curated the solution and important is why are we doing it we are doing it
to sustain you know better risk landscape for
India for the Entays very important so
grade perspective no I think now our
audience has a better clarity on risk
management so as we near the end of this
episode I have just one final question for
you so can you please guide our audience how
organizations can better leverage risk
management in your opinion how can they
shift their view of risk management not just as a
tool for  Threat mitigation but
also as a strategic enabler that
uncovers new opportunities
what is Khushbu so successful risk management
is basically to transform the uncertainties
into opportunities that's how we take those
opportunities you know so that opportunity comes
with innovation with your regulator
to overcome the regulatory challenge all
those are basically enlisted in the aao 31000 which
is a standard for the risk
management and there are other standards which also
help the risk management
standards are on basically the aao 14000 which talks about the
environment the 45000 which
talks about process safety the safety
and hazard so it's basically
an osha standard which has been
converted into aao 45000 and this is very important
you know to avoid any loss  And you know, keep an eye
on the emerging trends. So here,
basically, what is important is
to work on this. A comprehensive study
and regular risk assessment are also very
important to identify
a company as a risk partner. We can be a
partner with them on the risk because we
understand the losses. We have learned
from the industry losses and we can pass
on that. You know, enormous experience, which we have to better understand the risk. That's also important that
the organization
propagates what you know in their culture. It's about
finding out near misses, finding out
unsafe
conditions, and propagating them to you. Come
out in the open, investigate these kinds of
faults, and use it for their corrective action
so that it is not repeated again. So, in the
end,  It's important that the risk is the
customer's focus and you know partner with the
insurance company and we do a wonderful
risk management exercise together for a
win-win situation of both sots an excellent
response burgeon yes the saying goes
prevention is better than cure it is now
clear that conducting regular risk
management assessments and having the right
risk management tools in place
organizations can you know avoid any kind
of grave financial impact absolutely it's
important that we know we do it
proactively for the risks of the
organization absolutely thank you burgeon and
audience for tuning in today remember
risk is an inevitable part of business but
with the right strategy and tools
organizations can take charge if you enjoyed
today's episode please subscribe and leave
a review we'll see you next time
on episode four of oil cafe season two the
strategy ball
[music]